SADAQAT BARKAT

Mobile No. 0302-4214486/0334-4228542 Email: sabarkat17@hotmail.com



BRIEF PROFILE

Possessing 20 years of work experience in Administration, Human Resources & Accounts in the Educational services sector. A self-made personality, highly confident, creative, goal-oriented professional and highly organized with the ability to manage multiple responsibilities & meet deadlines. A strong work ethic combined with a commitment to excellence in all responsibilities undertaken. An enthusiastic and proactive individual with a logical approach to challenges, able to perform effectively with a highly pressurized working environment.

EXPERIENCE

The Trust School (TEDDS) Corporate Head Office, Lahore.

March 2019 ~Todate

Admin. & Procurement Manager

Responsibilities:-

- ✓ Reporting the General Secretary & CEO and Administrator; a key role in the management of TEDDS/The Trust Schools to ensure operations adhering to policies and regulations. Supervision of administrative functional activities and support in day-to-day operations of all the Campuses and plan the most efficient administrative procedures. Procuring high quality cost efficient supplies for the Campuses.
- ✓ Analyze the workload after data collection from all the Admin Officers of the Campuses and find out manpower overstaffing/deficiency and report to the CEO/Administrator.
- ✓ Liaison with Admin Officers for taking daily attendance reports and update to the CEO/Administrator.
- ✓ Plan and coordinate administrative procedures and devise ways to streamline processes.
- ✓ Assess administrative staff performance and provide them guidance to ensure maximum efficiency.
- ✓ Ensure the smooth and adequate flow of information within the Campuses.
- ✓ Keep abreast with all organizational changes and business developments.
- ✓ Maintain confidentiality.
- ✓ Oversee and draw up a plan for the purchase of equipment, services and supplies.
- ✓ Purchasing of new material for all the Campuses of The Trust Schools and Head Office with approval of higher authorities with attention to budgetary constraints.
- ✓ Meet with Vendors/Stake holders to maintain goods cost and quality consciousness.
- ✓ Monitor inventory of Office supplies, cleaning material/equipment etc. at all the Campuses.
- ✓ Maintain and update record of current and incoming approved purchases
- ✓ Security supervision monitoring of CCTV cameras.

Alma Mater Preschool, Lahore, Pakistan

July 2016 ~ Sept. 2018

Admin. Manager / Secretary to Principal

Responsibilities:-

- ✓ Organizing and scheduling the meetings of Principal. Scheduling appointments and Calendar.
- ✓ To provide administrative, secretarial & HR functional activities support to the Principal.
- ✓ Dealing with Admissions, Front Office duties meet with Vendors, Govt. Officers and Visitors etc.
- ✓ Accounts handling Fee collection, maintain Fee Ledger Book, Cash book, petty cash handling etc.
- ✓ Issuance of Fee Vouchers to students Termly. Parents' queries resolution by telephone/meetings.
- ✓ Supervision of General Administration, Ensure provision of maintenance and cleanliness work with the help of Janitorial staff. Check their performance and work twice a day and guidance given.
- ✓ Security supervision monitoring of CCTV cameras.
- ✓ Public dealing (telephonic enquiries) & assistance in preparing all documentations of the Principal.

Aitchison College Lahore, Pakistan

Jan. ~ Dec. 2015

Admin. Officer/ PA to Principal

A Pakistani pioneer and prestigious education Institute having students strength of almost 2600 with hostel facilities and a high standard of quality education.

Responsibilities:-

- ✓ Organizing and scheduling the meetings of the Principal with Teachers, HODs and Headmasters.
- ✓ To provide administrative, secretarial & HR functional activities like Employees' relation matters. Scheduling appointments and Calendar.
- ✓ Coordinating in Teachers' Performance and Continuous Staff development. Assistance in Training & Development of Teachers.
- ✓ Public dealing got telephonic enquiries and replied them telephonically or through courier, email, etc.
- ✓ Assistance in preparing all documentations of the Principal.

Beaconhouse School System – Corporate Group Head Office, Lahore.

May 1, $2004 \sim Apr$, 2012

Assistant Manager Human Resources

A Pakistani Group of companies having staff strength of over 8,000 employees with a branch network in all the major cities of Pakistan and all over the world like UK, Malaysia, Oman, UAE, Bangladesh, etc.

Responsibilities:-

- ✓ Coordinating in Company policies and procedures implementation, handling HR functional activities like Recruitment & Selection (Preparation of Job Descriptions, CV Screening, Phone calls to incumbents and conducting the Interviews, Departmental Orientation and Induction, Preparation & issuance of Appointment/Contact Letters, Custodian of Employees Personnel Record and timely up-gradation, Issuance of Employees Attendance Card, Ensure the EOBI, Health Insurance and Social security cards issuance), Compensation & Benefits (Payroll administration), Assistance in Performance Management, Assistance in Training & Development. Also Liaise with other regional offices regarding HR issues.
- ✓ Supervision all the matters related to Administrative functions including Office discipline controlling over Time & Leave Management System Record.

Cathedral School System, Lahore, Pakistan.

1988 ~1998 (10 years)

Officer – Administration

One of the Pakistan's leading Educational System under the management of Bishop Irfan Jamil (Bishop of Lahore) having students strength of 5,000 with 1000 employees with a branch network in Pakistan.

Responsibilities:-

- ✓ Supervision of all administrative functions like Procurement, Time & leave management, Accounts function of administrating the Staff salary of 45 employees; also generated a Fee System on Computer for the students, Fee reconciliation with the Bank, Book keeping (Cash book, Ledger) Tax handling, PF,EOBI, Fees making & rolling out monthly, Preparation of Annual Budget, Preparation of Reports for Auditing etc.
- ✓ Supervision of Event management in conducting students Excursion Trips, Teachers Trips, Seminars, Workshops, Fun Fair, Parents Day and other meetings etc. Also Supervision of all Classes Question Papers, making by Typewriter, stenciling machine and on Computer. Assistance in all the correspondence/documentations of the Principal.

QUALIFICATIONS

✓	MCS (Master in Computer Sciences)	1998-2000
	Kings College of Computer & Management Sciences,	

Gulberg III, Lahore.

✓ Graduation (B.A.,)

1994-1995

University of the Punjab, Lahore.

1990-1991

✓ Intermediate (F.A.,)
Board of Intermediate & Secondary Education, Lahore

✓ Matriculation 1988

Board of Intermediate & Secondary Education, Lahore.

✓ Others qualifications:

Diploma in Computer Applications with distinction marks of 1st position in the College. Diploma in typing with 40 words per minute.

TRAININGS/WORKSHOPS ATTENDED:

- ✓ 'Managing Change' One day Training conducted by School of Leadership.
- ✓ 'Exceptional Motivation' One day training at Beaconhouse School System.
- ✓ 8 days on job training of 'Customer Services Communication' at PTCL.
- ✓ 5 days training on 'Office Procedures and Management, Documentation and Audit' at Beaconhouse.

SKILLS

- ✓ Excellent motivational and organizational skills.
- ✓ Good interpersonal and communication skills.
- ✓ Exceptional social skills.
- ✓ Computer literate and proficient I.T. skills

HOBBIES

Reading & Body-Building.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name: Barkat Jalal Din (Late)

Date of Birth : 17th May 1971 Marital Status : Married (4 Children)

Address : F. C. College, Christian Colony, Gulberg III, Lahore 54600.

Religion : Christianity Nationality : Pakistani

NIC # : 35202-9037576-9

REFERENCES

Will be furnished on request.